<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Raspberry-Pi on Abe's Portfolio</title><link>https://habet.dev/tags/raspberry-pi/</link><description>Recent content in Raspberry-Pi on Abe's Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:49:45 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://habet.dev/tags/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Self Hosting and Securing Web Services Out of Your Home With Cloudflare Tunnel</title><link>https://habet.dev/blog/self-hosting-and-securing-web-services-out-of-your-home-with-cloudflare-tunnel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:49:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://habet.dev/blog/self-hosting-and-securing-web-services-out-of-your-home-with-cloudflare-tunnel/</guid><description>Why a tunnel? Opening up a port on a home network isn’t the greatest idea. It is a security risk, a hole waiting for a hacker/bot to sneak in using a known vulnerability. Many ISP‘s and routers prevent you from opening up ports 80 and 443. Another challenge you will face is setting up a dynamic DNS. Finally, when your domain is pointing to your home IP address it is very easy to determine your home location.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Encrypted Boot With Ssh</title><link>https://habet.dev/blog/raspberry-pi-encrypted-boot-with-ssh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:39:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://habet.dev/blog/raspberry-pi-encrypted-boot-with-ssh/</guid><description>Please note this project is a fork from ViRb3, I&amp;rsquo;ve made some minor changes here.
Tested on Raspberry Pi 3B &amp;amp; 4B with Ubuntu Server 21.04 &amp;amp; Debian 11
Introduction This guide will show you how to encrypt your Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s root partition and set up an initramfs that will prompt for the password, decrypt the partition and gracefully resume boot. You will also learn how to enable SSH during this pre-boot stage, allowing you to unlock the partition remotely.</description></item><item><title>Self Hosted</title><link>https://habet.dev/blog/self-hosted/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 22:41:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://habet.dev/blog/self-hosted/</guid><description>This blog is self hosted on a small raspberry pi. Smaller than the size of your hand. I choose this model with a Crucial SSD you can find here. You’ll need a wire like this to connect them.
Lid closed
Lid open
Raspberry pi sever
The OS of choice is Debian 11 because of its stability. I always prefer to encrypt my hardware, so I have nothing to worry about if it lands in other hands.</description></item></channel></rss>